Muneeb Ahmed . Jarvis Consulting

I am a recent graduate from York University, where I earned a Bachelor's degree in Computer Science. I have 18 months of professional experience as a Software Engineer. At AiFocal, I led the development of a project called Defai, which enabled users to create AI chatbots without coding, as well as integrating with messaging platforms like WhatsApp. My experience includes working with frontend technologies such as Next.js, React, TypeScript, and Tailwind CSS. I also contributed to backend components to ensure functionality, security, and accessibility for high-traffic web applications. I am enthusiastic to bring my experience and expertise to new challenges in the software industry. My goal is to develop products that make technology accessible and efficient for everyone.

Skills

Proficient: Java, Nextjs/React, RDBMS/SQL, Agile/Scrum, Git

Competent: Linux/Bash, JavaScript/TypeScript, Nodejs, Docker, Python

Familiar: AWS, LLMs, Python, Redux, Figma

Jarvis Projects

Project source code: https://github.com/jarviscanada/jarvis_data_eng_MuneebAhmed

Cluster Monitor [GitHub]: Developed a Linux Cluster Monitoring Agent to monitor hardware specs and usage across Linux clusters. Used Bash for automation, PostgreSQL for data management, Docker for container management, and Git for version control. The project simplifies system monitoring with automated scripts and a PostgreSQL database, enabling system admins and developers to optimize performance. Features include real-time data collection, automated database updates, and essential insights into system health. Future plans include updating hardware spec changes and integrating data visualization tools.

Core Java Apps [GitHub]:

- Twitter App: Curabitur laoreet tristique leo, eget suscipit nisi. Sed in sodales ex. Maecenas vitae tincidunt dui, et eleifend quam.
- JDBC App: Curabitur laoreet tristique leo, eget suscipit nisi. Sed in sodales ex. Maecenas vitae tincidunt dui, et eleifend quam.
- Grep App: Curabitur laoreet tristique leo, eget suscipit nisi. Sed in sodales ex. Maecenas vitae tincidunt dui, et eleifend quam.

Springboot App [GitHub]: Not Started

Python Data Analytics [GitHub]: Not Started

Hadoop [GitHub]: Not StartedSpark [GitHub]: Not Started

Cloud/DevOps [GitHub]: Not Started

Highlighted Projects

Rookery: Developed a serverless bird identification learning website using Nextjs and AWS Amplify. Users can learn about Toronto birds in a fun and interactive way by doing engaging quizzes. This was created to make learning free for Toronto bird watchers. These quizzes are stored and managed using GraphQL, DynamoDB and AWS S3. Enhanced user experience by tracking and saving individual progress using AWS authentication.

FitAI [GitHub]: Built FitAI, a Next.js web application that uses AI to help users craft personalized workout plans. Users fill out their current health and fitness goals through a modern and user friendly form designed using Mantine, and OpenAI API is used for generating the customized workout content. FitAI ensures secure user authentication and real time database updates using Firebase.

Professional Experiences

Technical Consultant, Jarvis (2024-present): Developed comprehensive full-stack software solutions as part of Jarvis's team, focusing on leveraging Java, Linux/Bash, RDBMS/SQL, Agile/Scrum methodologies, and Git for efficient

project management and deployment. Collaborated closely with cross-functional teams to design, implement, and refine scalable applications, enhancing business operations and user experiences

Software Engineer, AiFocal Inc. (2023-2023): Led a project called Defai, a no-code platform for AI chatbots, utilizing LLM tools like Langchain and Flowise. Ensured high traffic mangement and reliable security for a traffic load of 10,000 concurrent users by using microservice architecture. Created a fast and user friendly UI by utilizing Next.js, TypeScript, and Tailwind CSS for front-end UI and architecture.

Software Engineer, Boop (2023-2023): Engineered and maintained front-end components for Boop's landing page and business portal using Nextjs, Typescript and Tailwind CSS. Optimized website performance by 30% by introducing server side rendering and reusable react server components.

Software Engineer, Rove (2020-2021): Contributed to client-side projects at Rove, focusing on creating responsive and accessible applications using React, Mantine, Node.js, and Tailwind CSS. Ensured seamless functionality across different devices and browsers using BrowserStack. Integrated APIs and participated in Agile/Scrum processes for iterative development and continuous improvement.

Education

York university (2019-2023), Bachelor of Science, Computer Science

Miscellaneous

- Semi-Professional Esports Player
- Graphic Designing Behance
- Volunteer, NEST: Volunteered for event management for Esports Tournaments at NEST